Benjamin Parry

Asset Engineer

in linkedin.com/in/benjamin-parry □ +61 456 066 328 @ bparry@gmail.com

♀ 3 River EsplanadeMooloolaba 4557, QLD

i Available at 5 weeks notice period with current employer

Summary Statement

With a strong background in working in asset management and with various data systems, and having diverse career experience, from design and consulting in civil and structural engineering, international project management for large scale infrastructure management projects, in both public and private organisations, I have a unique range of that I'll use to bring value to any company.

Although most recently working in an information analyst role, my goal is to return to a position in an engineering role, where i have the opportunity to design creative solutions to difficult problems using the skills I've developed over my career, with the goal of completing my professional registration and becoming chartered.

CAREER SUMMARY

2018 - Present	Information Analyst, University of the Sunshine Coast
2016 - 2018	Technical Officer (Asset Management), Noosa Council
2012 - 2016	Project Manager (Asset Management), Soletanche-Freyssinet
2010 - 2012	Civil Engineer, Newton Denny Chapelle
2007 - 2008	Structural Engineer, GHD Engineering
2006 - 2007	Structural Engineer, Trackstar Alliance



PROFESSIONAL CAREER

Present July 2018

Information Analyst, University of the Sunshine Coast, Sunshine Coast

18 | Australian University

STRATEGIC INFORMATION AND ANALYSIS UNIT

Responsible for the Student Load and Income Forecasting model, undertak- ing data analysis and reporting.

- > Preparation and modelling of income forecasts, tracking university performance and executive reporting
- > Submission of estimates to Australian Government for Commonwealth funding
- > Collaborating with Marketing teams to assess trends and build market intelligence
- > Developing ad-hoc tools in Python and R to transform and use data
- > Requirements analysis and development to build PowerBI reports to respond to internal needs SQL Excel Python PowerBI Forecasting

July 2018 July 2016

Technical Officer, Noosa Council, Noosa

Local Council for the Noosa Shire

ASSET MANAGEMENT TEAM

Business Owner for Council's strategic asset management systems.

- > Consultation and liaison with operational and capital works departments to compile 5 year pavement reseal program.
- > Responsible for data integration and pavement deterioration modelling in SMEC.
- > Modelling and analysis of risk-based stormwater network inspection prioritisation model to help coordinate inspection campaigns.
- > Preparation of the Asset Information Management Strategy to structure data collection processes used in the organisation to collect consistent and valuable asset and works data, and integrate with other departments.
- > Building confidence in asset management across the organisation by working with engaging all with all departments providing awareness sessions.
- > Works liaison in Noosa Council Disaster Management Coordination Centre.
- > Implemented disaster information collection process for the National Disaster Relief and Recovery Arrangements for disaster funding and presentation of process at Technology One Local Government conference.

Asset management | Pavement management | Deterioration modelling | SAM | SMEC PMS | R | Python | Excel | QGIS |

March 2016 October 2012

Project Manager (Asset Management), VINCI SA / SOLETANCHE-FREYSSINET, Paris, France

Global construction with expertise in specialised building, civil, hydraulic, and electrical engineering ADVITAM GROUP

Technical lead and project manager for international asset management projects.

- > Managing up to 5 projects following agile PMBOK style methodology (Freyssinet PM+) for project life cycle
- > Preparation of Maintenance and Inspection plans for highways (PR1Bina, Aegean Motorway), bridges (Normandy, Vasco de Gama, Rion-Antirion), tunnels (Duplex A86), and water networks (Tucson Water, Great Man-Made River Project)
- > Implementation of pavement deterioration modelling for highway concessions
- > Coordinating development of infrastructure management systems to meet client requirements
- > Specification and delivery for structural monitoring data capture instruments and analysis of outputs
- > Delivering presentations, and coordinating and leading training sessions with clients
- > Commercial representation at conferences, and preparation of offers and bid submissions
- > Undertaking structural inspection campaign for A86 'Duplex' tunnel, Paris, France

Project management | Pavement management | Deterioration modelling | Asset management | Asset inspections | Site supervision | ScanPrint IMS | SAM |

October 2012 March 2010

Civil Engineer, Newton Denny Chapelle, Lismore

Town Planning/Civil Engineering/Surveying consultancy for industrial, residential and commercial developments.

CIVIL ENGINEERING

Undertaking preliminary and detailed engineering analyses and designs and managing consulting projects.

- > Stormwater modelling and design using MUSIC, CivilCAD and XP-RAFTS and preparation of design plans and documentation
- > Civil design including subdivisions, earthworks, pavement, stormwater and services
- > Preparation and submissions of technical engineering report to support development applications
- > Ensuring conformity with all relevant standards and regulations in design and supervision of construction quality
- > Negotiating development approval conditions and requirements on behalf of the client

 Civil design
 Project management
 Stormwater modelling
 Pavement design
 CivilCAD
 MUSIC
 XP-Rafts

 Site Supervision

November 2008 December 2007

Structural Engineer, GHD ENGINEERING, Brisbane

Engineering company in water, energy and resources, environment, property and buildings, and transportation.

MINING & INDUSTRIAL STRUCTURES DEPARTMENT

Part-time - Undergraduate engineer modelling and preparing designs and project specifications.

- > Modelling and design using Space Gass and STRAND7
- > Preparation of technical specifications and project documentation and design criteria Structural Engineering | STRAND | Space Gass |

November 2007 July 2006

Civil/Structural Engineer, TRACKSTAR ALLIANCE, Brisbane

Alliance between Queensland Rail, Thiess, United Group, Connell Wagner and Maunsell AECOM to rail projects in SEQ.

CONNELL WAGNER

Part-time - work experience role preparing structural designs and rail alignments for a rail duplication project.

- > Design of retaining walls, slabs and rail bridges and alignments
- > Site Supervision during service location and site preparation

Structural Design Site Supervision

EDUCATION

2016-2018 Graduate Diploma in Data Science (Accelerated), Monash University

2009 Exchange to L'Institut National Polytechnique de Grenoble, France, completing final project in the Laboratoire des Ecoulements Géophysiques et Industriels (LEGI).

2004-2009 Bachelor of Engineering (Civil)/Bachelor of Arts (Spanish, French) - first class honours, University of Queensland, St Lucia.



Project Management

Agile project management, and trained in Freyssinet PM+ project management (PMBOK equivalent): commercial offers, negotiating contractual issues, planning, risks analysis, tracking project budgets, personnel and time management, quality management. Led delivery of up to 5 simultaneous projects, up to €250,000 with profit margins of 30%.

Asset Management

Wide experience delivering and implementing strategic and operational asset management solutions (primarily highway concessions and asset owners), and experience as business process owner/system administrator in local council. Pavement deterioration modelling including implementation and delivery with ScanPrint IMS and modelling in SMEC PMS. Preparation of asset inventory manuals, inspection and maintenance plans.

Engineering

Structural and civil design, including roads, stormwater, subdivisions, and retaining structures for development applications and detailed construction certificate plans.

Leadership

Managing teams of up to 5 software developers, database designers, and electrical and instrumentation engineers, including remotely, to deliver work on time and to specifications. Successfully led change management including organisation wide asset management practices, implementation of supervision and reporting structures, and disaster management data collection processes to meet both internal and external requirements. Selected to represent Noosa Council at Local Government Management Associations Leadership Challenge in 2017.

Communication

Successful work history with people from diverse disciplines and backgrounds in both national and international environments. Able to communicate ideas clearly and logically to ensure efficient teamwork. Part of a team that won the Vinci Innovation Prize for International Dissemination for software developed through collaboration with multiple clients

Reporting

Financial and performance reporting to management and executives, preparation of project documentation for large-scale, international projects, preparation of project experience returns to ensure insights transferred to both management and peers. Development and implementatin of reporting dashboards and executive reports for clients. Presenting project updates and delivering training sessions to clients and their sub-contractors, with largest involving 100 sub-contractors

Analytics

Data capture, cleansing, integration and use through statistical analysis and visualisations to provide insights. Developed risk model for storm water pipe infrastructure based on environmental and land use factors, as well as physical characteristics of pipe to optimise inspection campaigns.

Software

- > Engineering and CAD software (SMEC PMS, ScanPrint IMS, Civil CAD, AutoCAD, SIDRA, MUSIC, XP-Rafts, STRAND7, Space Gass)
- > Enterprise systems Microsoft SQL, Access, Office, Project, Excel, ERPs, Technology One
- > Programming languages (R, Python, vb.net),
- > Web development (Silverlight, html5),
- > GIS (QGIS, ArcGIS)

Canguages



◆ OTHER INTERESTS

- > Climbing, Running, Surfing, Lifesaving
- > Travel, Languages
- > Piano, Woodwork